# **Laura Duncan**

# Senior Supply Chain & Logistics Manager - Bunzl Distribution

Dublin, CA 94568

lauraduncan9\_o7y@indeedemail.com - (503) 740-3550

Supply Chain and Logistics professional with 13 years' experience spanning multiple industries. A consultative expert, driven to achieve company goals by developing strong supplier relationships, reducing costs and streamlining operations. A team player with a demonstrated record of adaptability within the most challenging of environments, and the confidence and history of presenting and working closely with executive management.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Senior Supply Chain & Logistics Manager

Bunzl Distribution - Tracy, CA -

2017-03 - Present

- Oversees and manages overall supply chain and logistics operations to maximize efficiency and minimize cost of the organizations supply chain.
- Maintains and manages an experienced team of buyers and approximately 400 domestic as well as international vendors.
- Guides specific objectives, policies, and processes regarding the purchasing functions among cross functional teams including sales, warehouse and corporate management.
- Operates inventory turns at 12.5 and an average fill rate of 98.5% consistently. Manages warehouse inventory dollars which fluctuation between 7.5-8MM
- Effectively tracks and reports key functional metrics across the branch with regard to vendor performance, quality and cost.
- Partner with key stakeholders to ensure clear requirements and documentation at national and local level.
- Perform cost scenario/analysis and benchmark certain commodities associated with primary customers.
- Forecast price and market trends in order to identify changes in the market place and reduce and disruptions and volatility in the supply chain
- Continually seek and develop relationships with reliable vendors that support our core competency as a distributor and supply chain partner.

# **Senior Purchasing Manager**

Foster Farms - Livingston, CA -

2015-11 - 2017-03

- Provide purchasing support for ordering and budgeting for internal/external fleet requirements; assist in budgeting, planning, financial justification and acquisition of various MRO equipment and capital investments
- Evaluate suppliers and products to issue sound recommendations; coordinate inventory management turns and costs to maximize RONA benefits while insuring adequate supplies
- Initiate, develop and issue RFP's and evaluate competitive bids; provide financial analysis that drives source selection
- Develop recommendations targeted to deliver most favorable Quality, Cost, Timing, Service, Safety and Technology

- Negotiate and draft contracts for acquisition; establish performance guarantees for customer protection
- Provide support in the creation of strategic purchasing plans that support the budgeting, planning, financial justification, acquisition and requirements of our Poultry, Turkey & Dairy fleet requirements throughout the US
- · Provide support to ensure compliance with all local, state and federal regulations for fleet compliance

# **Logistics and Distribution Analyst**

Restaurant Services Incorporated - Miami, FL -

2012-07 - 2015-11

- Strategically manage the flow and distribution of product from international manufacturer to local warehouses by maintaining constant communication with internal customers, managers and distribution centers
- Ensure the timely, efficient and cost-conscience delivery of product to 27 distribution centers under strict deadlines
- Reduced transportation costs \$10K monthly by implementing efficient supply transportation processes
- Analyze historical sales data to ensure adequate inventory levels among regional domestic distribution centers
- Generate critical bi-monthly KPI reports and communicate findings to management; KPI reports monitor fill rates, inventory turns, cost per piece, delivery performance, cost of goods sold, etc.
- Schedule, implement and maintain time-sensitive and efficient outbound logistics plans and inventory levels; responsible for the timely execution of promotional items to Burger King restaurants
- Involved in contract negotiations with ocean carriers, capturing a \$150K annual cost savings by leveraging volume
- Serve as a trusted consultant to purchasing organization, providing essential support, advice and logistics expertise
- Collaborate with various carriers in coordinating domestic transportation and to analyze current shipping methods and truckload configurations; saved company +/- \$500K annually by adjusting cases per truckload on a high volume item, reducing the item's "landed cost"
- · Successfully manage the carrier RFP process, accepting and reviewing all carrier proposals
- Participate in mitigation risk analysis and the creation of "worst case scenario" contingency plans

# **Supplier Enablement Lead**

Ryder Systems - Miami, FL -

2011-09 - 2012-06

- Successfully trained hundreds of internal staff, vendors and suppliers on the functionality and use of new ecommerce Ariba Network; this major process overhaul resulted in significant cost savings and created a more educated user base
- Developed best practices among purchasing community within Ariba Network; implemented approved vendor list to streamline options; closely monitored user spend and set controls for internal purchases
- Strategically analyzed current field operations/processes and adapted to correspond with Ariba Network
- Initiated weekly support webinars for internal and external customers and served as liaison between vast supplier base and internal user community

# **Supply Chain Management Analyst III**

The Boeing Company - Portland, OR -

2008-01 - 2011-09

Commercial Airplanes, Fabrication Division)

- Responsible for +/- 300 Flight Controls Systems and Equipment parts; improved all metrics by closely monitoring and holding suppliers accountable for performance around lead time, delivery performance, inventory, yields and cycle time
- Utilized Oracle ERP system and supporting systems to place timely and quantity-accurate orders that met our Supply Chain Management needs; maintained synchronization of supply chain between various customers and suppliers by successfully managing, validating and verifying MRP data
- Collaborated and maintained open lines of communication with ME Planning, MFG ENG, Global Partners, Information Technology, Quality Assurance, shipping and receiving and other departments regarding system, process improvements and LEAN principles
- Supported achievement of quarterly management goals by providing metrics to support analysis of supply chain; closely monitored inventory levels and adjusted accordingly based on findings
- Successfully reduced excess inventory by 35% by improving supplier's JIT program while functioning in a lean environment
- Executed external customer and supplier plans to reduce material and product variability and arrive at optimal solutions
- Ensured cost-effective execution and timely delivery by effectively managing schedules and coordinating with customer support representatives, contract administration, purchasing, engineering, quality assurance, traffic and warehousing
- Significantly reduced costs and met Global Purchasing cost savings targets by negotiating and establishing a new pricing contract based on annual spend
- Analyzed and detected a procurement inefficiency; implemented a Blanket Purchase Agreement in conjunction with JIT to ensure flow of product and avoid line shut down; significantly reduced cycle time for packaging receiving process
- Responsible for daily schedule maintenance & accuracy, purchase order release performance, item order maintenance, new item maintenance, spares, cycle counting, reconciling of shipping and receiving discrepancies as well as routine communications with suppliers and customers

# **Buyer-Global Supply Chain**

Xerox Corporation - Wilsonville, OR -

2006-08 - 2007-12

#### Transport Service Buyer

Integrity Logistics - Wilsonville, OR -

2004-06 - 2006-08

**EDUCATION** 

# MBA in Supply Chain Management

Nova Southeastern University

2015-06

# **BA in Supply and Logistics Management**

Portland State University